<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:id="chapter.instant.start.guide">
  <title xml:id="chapter.instant.start.guide.title">Introduction to OmegaT</title>

  <section xml:id="introduction.omegat.principles">
    <title xml:id="introduction.omegat.principles.title">Principles</title>

    <para>Welcome to OmegaT, a computer-assisted translation (CAT) tool that
    offers great flexibility, performance and robustness, as well as features
    beyond those of commercial offerings, even for beginning translators.</para>

    <para>An OmegaT translation project consists of a number of resources
      stored in separate folders, of an <filename>omegat.project</filename>
      file that stores the location of all the resources and of a <filename>project_save.tmx</filename>
      translation memory file that stores all the translations made while
      working on that project.</para>
    <para>Translators can easily modify the contents or location of those
      resources at any time during the translation.</para>

    <para>By default, resources include the project’s translation memory,
      which is automatically created upon project creation, and the files to
      translate. They can also include reference translation memories,
      glossaries, and other reference files.</para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="introduction.omegat.principles.translation.memories">
    <title
            xml:id="introduction.omegat.principles.translation.memories.title">Translation
      memories</title>

    <para>Translators do not have to <emphasis>create</emphasis> a translation
      memory or <emphasis>associate</emphasis> one to a new project. OmegaT
      takes care of that <emphasis>automatically</emphasis>.</para>

    <para>Translators can very easily reuse an existing projectʼs translation
      memory by simply adding new translation files to an existing project, or by
      copying an existing translation memory to a new project.</para>

    <para>There is no limit to the number of translation memories that can be
      used as reference in a translation project, and OmegaT makes it very easy
      to assign different levels of priority to these additional
      memories.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
